Steven H. Walinski

17 Minden Street Depew, NY, 14043 (716) 462-7631

stevenwalinski@yahoo.com Portfolio:

https://github.com/shwalins/portfolio

Profile

Recently graduated from University at Buffalo with a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science. Has had simulated experiences such as Software Development within classroom environments and excelled with skills such as organization, discipline, and communication. Offers remarkable work ethics such as precise attention to detail within a timely manner, dedication to the task at hand, and maintaining both focus and a professional attitude in the most agile situations. To view my work, such as past and current projects, please look at my portfolio linked above.

Skills

- Proficient with Python, C/C++, Java Agile Methodologies Critical Thinking Object Oriented Programming
- Git Version Control Linux Environment Communication Test-Driven Development Organization
- Tenacity Self Improving Time Management Quick Learning Self-Confident Documentation

Employment History

BuzzCutz Landscaping

Depew, New York

Landscaper

June 2010 - September 2011, April 2017 - Present

Provided landscaping services to clients all over Western New York. With multiple job sites, multiple clients expect satisfactory work on a weekly basis to which those expectations are both met and surpassed. Landscaping services included weekly mowing, weeding, bush maintenance, and on demand tasks such as mulching.

■ Provided exceptional services on a weekly basis to multiple clients.

Marco Promotional Management

Production & Picker/Packer

Williamsville, New York July 2014 – April 2017

As Production: worked with a team on an assembly line repackaging products and stacking them on a pallet to be stored in the warehouse for later use.

As Picking/Packing: received multiple orders daily that called for product stored within the warehouse. Product would be picked and packaged/stacked on a pallet and readied to be shipped. Worked with product inventory via receiving and processing orders.

- Worked as a Team Lead while on Production. Responsibilities include filling out proper paper work and leadership over a team of 2-4.
- Worked with shipping programs that called for accurate information and knowledge of shipping rates.
- Maintained warehouse inventory while new and old product was consistently coming and going.

McDonald'sDepew, New YorkCrew MemberApril 2012 – January 2015

Delivered exceptional service by greeting and serving customers in a timely, friendly manner. Performed closing duties such as restocking and cleaning/maintenance. Exercised both accuracy and speed while working in the grill and delivering food to customers.

- Delivered extraordinary customer service through communication and professionalism.
- Maintained professionalism and positive attitude throughout all stressful situations.

Education

University At Buffalo – August 2015 – December 2017

Buffalo, New York

Graduated with a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

Erie Community College – September 2013 – May 2015

Williamsville, New York

Completed required coursework and transferred to University at Buffalo to pursue a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

Depew High School – Graduated June 2013

Depew, New York

Received Advanced Regents diploma with Mastery in Math & Science

Accomplishments

Achieved Mastery in Math & Science with Advanced Regents Diploma

Geico Scholarship recipient

Graduated High School with a GPA of 95

8x NYSPHSAA Scholar Athlete

Dean's List - Erie Community College Fall 2013

Community Involvement

- Member of the clubs: TV Broadcasting, Students Against Destructive Decisions.
- Member of High School mixed chorus, concert choir, and show choir for four years.
- Involved in High School Football and Wrestling sport teams for four years.
- Sang and acted in various roles for four years as part of Depew High School's musicals.
- Completed 40 Hours of Community Service as part of the Confirmation Program through Our Lady of Pompeii Parish.